astellas.com 2019-06-22

# Privacy Policy | Astellas Pharma Inc. GLOBAL WEBSITE

##  Personal Information Protection Policy

Astellas Pharma Inc. ("Astellas Pharma") duly acknowledges the importance of protecting personal information. Accordingly, Astellas Pharma complies with the laws, regulations, and rules concerning personal information, and it endeavors to handle and manage personal information both properly and safely.  
Astellas Pharma acts in accordance with the following provisions concerning the handling of personal information.

#### 1.Acquisition of Personal Information

Astellas Pharma will acquire the personal information by lawful and fair means.

#### 2.Use of Personal Information

Astellas Pharma will use the personal information only for the purposes of use which Astellas Pharma has already notified or publicly announced on this website. Astellas Pharma will not use the personal information beyond the scope necessary to achieve these purposes of use, without the concerned person's consent.

In case that Astellas Pharma shares the personal information with its overseas subsidiary companies, it will use the personal information in accordance with all applicable laws and regulations.

In case that Astellas Pharma entrusts a third party contractor with the business of handling the personal information in whole or in part, it will check and select a contractor capable of properly managing the personal information as its contractor. Astellas Pharma will agree with the contractor the matters necessary to protect the entrusted personal information, and will exercise necessary and appropriate supervision over the contractor to ensure the security control of the entrusted personal information. In case that Astellas Pharma jointly uses the personal information with a third party, it will notify the concerned person about the matters prescribed in laws and regulations, including the scope of use by the person jointly using the personal information, or will publicly announce these matters on this website, prior to jointly sharing the personal information with the third party.

#### 3.Provision of Personal Information to a Third Party

(1)Astellas Pharma will not provide the personal information to any third party, except in any of the following cases.

  1. Cases in which the concerned person's prior consent is obtained;
  2. Cases in which the personal information is disclosed in a manner that cannot identify the concerned person;
  3. Cases in which disclosure of the personal information is required by laws and regulations or by a public entity, such as a court or the police; or
  4. Cases in which disclosure of the personal information is otherwise acceptable under laws and regulations.

(2) Notwithstanding the foregoing, Astellas Pharma will provide the following personal information of the Healthcare Professionals ("HCPs") to HCPs, its subsidiary companies and organizations, wholesalers and pharmaceutical companies, when it has business reasons to do so. In case that Astellas Pharma receives a request from the concerned person, it will take reasonable action after confirmation of identity.

1\. items to provide  
name, email address, business office, business address, business telephone, specialty, title, graduation year, graduation college, year of practice, membership of academic society and/or medical society, sales result, etc.

2\. way of provision  
verbal, writing, electronic way, etc.

#### 4.Control of Personal Information

Astellas Pharma will maintain the personal data accurate and conduct security control of such personal data. Moreover, Astellas Pharma will prevent loss, damage, falsification, leaks to outside the company, and unauthorized external access; as well, it will undertake strict security measures to manage the personal data safely. Astellas Pharma will adopt SSL encrypted coding for a certain part of its website content.

#### 5.Disclosure of Retained Personal Data, etc.

In case that any person who is subject to Astellas Pharma's retained personal data requests to disclose, correct, discontinue the utilization of, or erase the retained personal data, Astellas Pharma will appropriately respond to such request within the reasonable scope.

#### 6.Internal Organization and Structure

Astellas Pharma will appoint company-wide personal information managers. Moreover, Astellas Pharma will supervise its employees handling the personal information and implement necessary and appropriate education and training for such employees to ensure the protection of the personal information.

##  Purpose of the Use of Personal Information

Astellas Pharma will acquire personal information, with specifying its purpose of the use and will retain and use the personal information in an appropriate manner to the extent necessary to its businesses. Its purpose of the use of personal information is as follows:

### 1\. Personal Information on Healthcare Professionals

  * To provide, collect, review and communicate information on the proper use of drugs, medical devices, drug samples, and other goods and products handled by Astellas Pharma(hereinafter referred to collectively as "Medical Products");
  * To provide, collect, review and communicate information on quality, safety or effectiveness of Medical Products;
  * To provide, collect, review and communicate healthcare-related information;
  * To report on the occurrence of adverse effect, accident, recall of Medical Products;
  * To check, review and take reasonable action to request for information and inquiry,
  * To take hold of delivery destinations and improve their network of specified biological products;
  * To conduct research of delivery destinations, actual use, and user's needs of Medical Products;
  * To request and implement clinical study, postmarketing surveillance study and other studies;
  * To conduct research studies in medical and pharmaceutical fields;
  * To conduct membership management and certification on websites for healthcare professionals;
  * To disclose information in accordance with "Transparency Guidelines for Collaborative Relationships between Astellas Pharma Inc. and Medical Institutions,"
  * To provide, collect, review and communicate information to support starting practice, hospital management, and medical cooperation;
  * To handle complaints about our products and services;
  * To cultivate better communication among Healthcare Professionals;
  * To make notifications and reports to government and other public offices and agencies;
  * To contact healthcare professionals regarding the above tasks.

### 2\. Personal Information on Those Who Belong to Wholesalers of Medical Products

  * To cooperate to drive efficient promotion of Medical Products;
  * To provide, collect, review and communicate information on quality, safety and effectiveness of Medical Products;
  * To cooperate in the occurrence of adverse effect, accident, recall of Medical Products;
  * To conduct research of delivery destinations, actual use, and user's needs of Medical Products;
  * To cultivate better communication; and
  * To contact those who belong to wholesalers of medical product regarding the above tasks.

### 3\. Personal Information on Scientists including Medical and Pharmaceutical Fields

  * To provide, collect, review and communicate academic information and information on the proper use of drug samples for study;
  * To conduct research of delivery destinations, actual use, and user's needs of drug samples for study;
  * To conduct research studies including medical and pharmaceutical fields;
  * To conduct membership management and certification on websites for scientists;
  * To respond to queries, and handle complaints, about products and services;
  * To cultivate better communication and
  * To contact biological scientists regarding the above tasks.

### 4\. Personal Information on Patients and General Public

  * To review, investigate and respond to details of consultations, queries and communications;  
 
  * To support patients association;
  * To install and maintain, respond queries and make explanation about, medical equipment and devices associated with home care business;
  * To provide information on forums and seminars on Medical Products and medical public seminar.
  * To plan and evaluate its disease state awareness activities; and
  * To conduct research and survey of medical use and/or medical needs.

### 5\. Personal Information on Participants in Clinical Studies (Subjects)

  * Astellas Pharma usually acquires the information on health damage compensation and the information on patients and participants in clinical studies under the necessary measures that specific individuals could not be identified, but may exceptionally acquire identifiable personal information. Astellas Pharma usually acquires the information on health damage compensation and the information on patients and participants in clinical studies under the necessary measures that specific individuals could not be identified, but may exceptionally acquire identifiable personal information; and
  * Human genome/gene analysis research: *Astellas usually does not obtain information with which an individual can be immediately identified, such as name, etc.; however, Astellas may obtain genome data that corresponds to individual identification codes.

### 6\. Personal Information on Those Who Made Use of Our Corporate Communications Department, Medical Information Center and Other Contacts

  * To review, investigate and respond to details of consultations, queries and communications;
  * To make reports and contact to the manufacturer, distributor and other agents of our product;
  * To make notifications and reports to government and other public offices and agencies; and
  * To contact those who made use of our corporate communications department , medical information center and other contacts regarding the above tasks.

### 7\. Personal Information on Those Who Belong to the Consignee, Consultant and Other Business Partners (including those who belong to their industry group and public agencies concerned)

  * To communicate, consult, confirm, request and give instruction to concerning the consigned and/or sponsored services;
  * To implement efficiently consigned and/or sponsored services;
  * To grasp their qualifications, occupational abilities and job experiences;
  * To cultivate better communication;
  * To make notifications and reports to government and other public offices and agencies; and
  * To contact those who belong to the consignee, consultant and other business partners regarding the above tasks.

### 8\. Personal Information on Shareholders

  * To send a notice of the shareholder meeting and a voting form of the shareholder meeting;
  * To pay dividends to shareholders;
  * To make a list of shareholders and give notice to a transfer agent; and Others:
  * To exercise its rights and perform its obligations under the law;
  * To give a wide variety of facilities to the position of its shareholder from Astellas Pharma;
  * To take measures of every kind in order to make our relationship with shareholders smooth; and
  * To manage shareholders, such as creating shareholder data according to the prescribed standards under a wide variety of laws and regulations.

### 9\. Personal Information on Media Representatives, Securities Analysts and Investors

  * To distribute news and information on Astellas Pharma;
  * To provide information on events;
  * To grasp and analyze our stakeholders' needs and make plans based on such needs;
  * To cultivate better communication; and
  * To contact media representatives, securities analysts and investors regarding the above tasks.

### 10\. Personal Information on Applicants for Employment and Applicants for Internship

  * To discuss and decide to adopt or reject applicants, and to respond to queries about the result of recruitment;
  * To contact applicants for employment regarding the above tasks;
  * To implement internship; and to refer to future planning and operation; and
  * To contact applicants for employment and applicants for internship regarding the above tasks.

### 11\. Personal Information on Employees (both those who hold an office and who retired from an office)

  * To plan and manage the personnel assignment, assessment, treatment, development, conditions of work, welfare program, safety and health;
  * To communicate with the labor union, benefit society, health insurance society, subsidiaries, affiliates and other organizations concerned;
  * To Communicate with the employee and his/her family members in case of emergency;
  * To grasp the record of attending on-the-job training classes, the results of examinations within the company;
  * To provide the record of attending MR training courses to MR education center;
  * To communicate with the consignees, consulting companies, insurance companies and other companies concerned;
  * To present the brief personal history externally;
  * To post personal information on printed materials to be distributed or provided internally or externally;
  * To make notifications and reports to government and other public offices and agencies; and
  * To make, manage and maintain a member list of retired employees reunion; and
  * To make contact, consult with employees about, and make queries about, the operation of the retired employees reunion.
